<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Arguments and materials for a register of estates</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1698</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 31 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 17 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A75547</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing A3638A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R208633</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">38875533</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 38875533</idno>
            <idno type="VID">152177</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A75547)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 152177)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2281:24)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Arguments and materials for a register of estates</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 30 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Samuel Lowndes ...</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London:</pubPlace>
                  <date>1698.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imperfect: print show-through.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Land titles --  Registration and transfer --  Great Britain.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:152177:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>ARGUMENTS AND MATERIALS FOR A Regiſter of Eſtates.</p>
            <figure>
               <q>Qui bene Dimidium facti cepit habet.</q>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed for <hi>Samuel Lowndes</hi> over againſt <hi>Exeter-Exchange</hi> in the <hi>Strand.</hi> 1698.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:152177:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:152177:2"/>
            <head>ARGUMENTS AND MATERIALS FOR A Regiſter of Eſtates.</head>
            <p>A Gentleman of the Long Robe happen'd lately to be in Compa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny with ſeveral Members of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, and others; where the Motion for a Regiſter of Eſtates in <hi>England</hi> (a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong other Parliamentary Affairs) fell in Diſcourſe: This occaſioned a particular application of the Company to that Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, for his Opinion; he was loath to come to, but at length, being warmed
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:152177:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>with Queſtions and Debates upon it and a few Glaſſes interſperſt, he ſurrendered himſelf to Diſcourſe, and ſeem'd to diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>play all his Sentiments to the ſatisfaction of the Company. After which, he was much preſt to digeſt his Thoughts, and publiſh them in Print; or at leaſt, com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>municate them in Writing to ſome parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cular Members of Parliament, in order to ſupport the Cauſe of a Regiſter, againſt the Oppoſition like to be made in the Houſe, by the Gentlemen of his Profeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion, or thoſe who practice as ſuch; but he would not be prevailed upon to do either; pretending, that true Friends in Publick, and faithful Truſtees in Private Concerns, ſeldom ſcape without ſcratcht Faces; and that with a ſeverity proportio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate with their Zeal and Sincerity; there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore he was determined to live in Peace, and meddle with neither. This Repulſe did not content me, but thinking I underſtood his Notions, and could ſet down, by way of Minutes, the material part of them; After I came to my Chamber, I went to
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:152177:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>Work accordingly, the Reſult whereof follows, <hi>viz.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="1">1. He ſaid, he was for a Regiſter; and thought if ſomewhat of that ſort were not done, the incertainty of Titles and Pedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grees would become an intolerable Grie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vance; and appear continually more and more, not only by the Frauds of Owners, cheating with double Conveyances; but Forgeries, which would increaſe as the Means of detecting them fell away.</p>
            <p n="2">2. That elder times have had the advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage of a Regiſtry, in great Eſtates, by Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fices <hi>Poſt Mortem,</hi> which recorded Matches, Iſſues, Deaths; Purchaſes and Settlements almoſt <hi>Verbatim;</hi> and for ſmall Eſtates, by the Rolls of Courts Baron and Surveys, where Tenures and Services were Regiſtred for the benefit of the Lords. And in thoſe days, no Conveyance could be Chambered over and over again, as now, by Leaſe and Releaſe; but muſt be done by Feoffment only, which had its force from publick Livery and Seiſin; and for his part, he ſaid, if it were <hi>res integra,</hi> and
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:152177:4" rendition="simple:additions"/>undermined, he ſhould give his Opinion, that a Leaſe and Releaſe, as now in com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon uſe, was not a legal Conveyance of Inheritances, but a meer Trick and Gim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crack of the Law; That the Vertue of Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fices <hi>Poſt Mortem,</hi> for diſcovery of Forge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries, and clearing of Pedigrees, is not yet altogether worn out, but very near it; And whereas the laſt Age hath had only that Aid (near ſpent as it is) for detecting of Forgeries, the next will have none at all; And at preſent there being little or no Guaranty of Titles, but the uncertain ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſty of Perſons, and that only as to their own Acts, the Trade for Land will ſink, and in the room, Fraud and Forgery ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vance.</p>
            <p n="3">3. That the Parliament have ever been hammering at a Reform by way of Regi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter, and ſometimes fancied they had it. For when the Servility of Tenures <hi>in Capite</hi> made People ſtudy Clandeſtine Settle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, that their Heirs might be free from Wardſhips and Marriage, the Lawyers found out the Trick of Uſes, which then
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:152177:4"/>was the ſame as we now call Truſts. And the Judges reſolved ſuch to be Diſpoſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able by Will, though Land it ſelf, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out a Burgh-Engliſh Cuſtom, was not ſo: Theſe Uſes aroſe by Bargain and Sale for Money, or Covenants to be ſeized for Conſideration of Blood, but moſtly the former. The Crown laboured againſt Uſes, as Deſtructive to the Preroga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tives of Tenure in Capite; Wherefore in 27. <hi>Henry</hi> 8. <hi>Cap.</hi> 10. the Statute was made to turn Uſes into Poſſeſſions, which was intended to take Uſes clean away. But the contrary happened, and it was ſoon found that moſt Purchaſes would paſs by Bargain and Sale; a Chamber Conveyance, like our Leaſe and Releaſe, which our Parliament thought would be a Practice moſt Miſchievous, as it was, and therefore, 27 <hi>Hen.</hi> 8. <hi>Cap.</hi> 16. it was Enacted, That Bargains and Sales ſhould be Void, unleſs Inrolled within ſix Months; Here they thought they had caught a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſter, but the more modern trick of Leaſe and Releaſe hath prevented it; and ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:152177:5" rendition="simple:additions"/>Law now, for which there is the ſame Reaſon, to make Leaſes and Releaſes Void, unleſs Inrolled in a time certain, would be almoſt a Regiſter, unleſs ſome yet newer Device were found out, like that, to Evade it.</p>
            <p>The Statute of Fines and Non-Claim, was a ſort of Regiſter and is uſeful ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cordingly at this day; for Thouſands of Fines are Leavied only to Gain, by Efflux of five years time, a Bar upon Record.</p>
            <p n="4">4. That it is ridiculous and ſenceleſs, in a Nation pretending to Literature and Law, That a Man ſhould be capable to Sell his Eſtate over and over again in the ſame Morning; and take the Money, and no one Purchaſer hath any human Means to know of the other. Our Neighbours are wiſe: For <hi>Scotland</hi> Regiſters an Ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtract: <hi>Holland</hi> Regiſters by the Tax of Sales; And the clearneſs of Titles acci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dentally reſulting from the Collectors Accounts of that Revenue, (for a Non-Payment of the Tax makes the Sale Void) is a recompence for the Tax it ſelf, though
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:152177:5"/>heavy, as he ſaid, even to 20 <hi>l. per Cent.</hi> of the Purchaſe Money. In <hi>France</hi> there is a Proceſs to clear Titles by Judgment, the method whereof, is, To fix on the Church-Door, a Monition for all Claim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to come in; and then after ſome Form's paſt, (which by the way, are much too ſlow and chargeable) the Land is at length, by Judgment, freed from all Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tles and Incumbrances whatſoever. In other Places almoſt all Contracts as well for Land as other Matters, are made by publick Officers, called Notaries, and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſtred. Nay, the <hi>Turks</hi> relie on <hi>Oggets</hi> or Decrees of the <hi>Caddes</hi> Regiſtred. And out little Nation of the Fens hath a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſter, which is approved by many years Practice, and may ſerve for a Model for the reſt of <hi>England.</hi> Therefore he won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred that this Kingdom is ſo long without their Convenience and Security; and in a matter that concerned them ſo Univer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſally, as their Purchaſes and Settlements among themſelves. He thought that af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter all he could ever hear Objected to a
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:152177:6"/>Regiſter, it could not be in Common Senſe right, that in any Nation, the Law ſhould be ſuch as that a wiſe and careful Man had no human Means, by Skill or Indu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtry, to be ſafe in his Dealing: <hi>Vigilanti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bus &amp; non Dormientibus obvenient Leges:</hi> But the Policy of late hath been ſo pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſterous, rather to lay Cuſhions for Fools to Blunder upon, than to provide Foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dations for the Wiſe and Careful: In former times it was a Reaſon of Law, Authentick in <hi>Weſtminſter-Hall, Que ſerra arrect ſa follie,</hi> and ſo for <hi>laches, &amp;c.</hi> And in latter Days, the Chancellors have ſaid in open Court, They ſat not there to relieve Fools. However pittyful we now are to careleſs and ſupine Men; it is a ſad thing, that for their Sakes, the wiſe and vigilant ſhould have no ſure Footing, and in his Opinion they never could have in <hi>England,</hi> unleſs a Regiſter of Eſtates, of ſome ſort or other, were Eſtabliſh'd.</p>
            <p>You may imagine, that this Emport<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of our Lawyers was no leſs divert<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing then a ſurpriſe, becauſe we all ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pected
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:152177:6"/>he ſhould have taken the ſide of moſt of his Profeſſion, to be againſt a Regiſter; and ſome could not forbear asking the Reaſon of his differing ſo much from them, in a Cauſe generally thought very oppoſite to their Intereſts; for many promoted a Regiſter in pique to the Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yers; and they on the other ſide, were obſerved to defend, as if the Freehold of their Profeſſion were at Stake: <hi>To this, ſaid he.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I do believe ſome Lawyers are mainly from that Motive againſt a Regiſter, others are ſo really, thinking unſeen Miſchieſs may ſpring from it, and ſo to the Publick, as well as to their Profeſſion; but on the other ſide, many, and of thoſe ſome Eminent Perſons have been for it. And I muſt a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gree conſidering both ſorts, generally ſpeaking, the moſt publick Spirited, and diſintereſted in Practice, have been, and are for it; and thoſe who court Buſineſs moſt, are againſt it. And if we reflect how the Intereſt inclines, we may con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clude, if Regiſters were not highly Uſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full,
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:152177:7" rendition="simple:additions"/>or rather neceſſary, you ſhould not have the ſingle Voice of a Lawyer for it; and that ſome have been ſo, is a greater Argument <hi>Pro,</hi> then all the reſt oppoſing is <hi>Contra.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>He mentioned my Lord Chief Juſtice <hi>Hales,</hi> that great Light of the Law, whoſe ſubtlety and foreſight ſuggeſted ſo many Caſualites upon a Regiſter, that he was afraid of the manner, rather than againſt the thing, as appears by his little Tract on that Subject, which hath been made publick; wherein he concludes with ſome Cautions to be had in the Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>delling; which ſhews he was not altoge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther againſt it. And he ſaid, He had al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo ſeen a Tract on the ſame ſubject by another Eminent Chief of his Time, who is earneſtly and clearly for a Regiſter; And he had converſt with many others of the Profeſſion of great Value, who were much for it.</p>
            <p>But he told us frankly, He thought the Lawyers were to be made uſe of by the Parliament, in a concern, ſuch as this
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:152177:7"/>is, as by a prudent Client, who Conſults them, but determines upon his own Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, and gains his Advantage out of their Skill, by ſmiting with Doubts and Que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtions, as for Fire from a Flint. A Man that in all his Affairs will blindly ſteer himſelf by regular Counſel; If by Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yers ſhall be ſtrangely intangled in his Buſineſs; if by Phyſitians, loſe his Health. A Prudent Man, vers'd in general Buſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, and a Lawyer, do well together, but either apart is not ſo well: It is the ſame in all other Arts and Profeſſions, the For<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mality of their Imployments oft-times wants a Ballaſt of Prudence. It was lately obſerved in the <hi>Chancery,</hi> That the beſt Advocates at the Bar did not make the beſt Judges upon the Bench; to ſay no worſe: For they were Bred and Pra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctic'd, even to an habit of Spinning Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vils and Exceptions, <hi>Pro</hi> and <hi>Con.</hi> and could not forbear, when they were above it. The Parliament ſhould uſe the Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yers as their Council, to put in Form, but make their own Bargains, and therein
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:152177:8"/>they have reaſon to expect their Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cils beſt Endeavours (according to their Profeſſion) to draw up, and execute in the beſt manner they can contrive, but ſhould not to be ruled by them, <hi>Pro</hi> or <hi>Con,</hi> poſitively upon the main; for that is matter of Policy and Conſtitution, more than Law: Bring any Buſineſs to a Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yer, he goes to work with it as with a Title, ſtudying Scruples; and treats it with a world of Subtlety, as if it were to be inſtantly Tryed, or he were to move in Arreſt of Judgment, or Quaſh an Indictment. A Legiſlator is a Spirit above a <hi>Chiccaneur,</hi> and muſt have a more comprehenſive Aim, than ſerves to kick down an Indictment or a Declaration. He concluded, it was a peculiar unhap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pineſs this matter had in Parliament that the Lawyers were ſo much hearkned too; he thought the other Members ought to underſtand ſo much, as not to hang upon their Tongues either way; nor to have their Eyes blinded with miſty Objections, which Intereſt and Partiality will ever be
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:152177:8"/>raiſing. As to the matter it ſelf, a great deal was ſaid, and I wiſh I could expreſs it with as much ſatisfaction as I heard it, but what I can Recollect, follows:</p>
            <p n="1">I. That if he were to Rule, every Man ſhould be obliged to Regiſter his laſt Conveyances, but knowing what a Bug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bear that is, and how apt to ſtartle Men, he was content to quit it, and that the Regiſter ſhould look only forwards, and be as Seed Sown in good Ground, to grow up, and get ſtrength gradually, and that more out of Incouragement then Compulſion.</p>
            <p n="2">II. Therefore it ſhould be Enacted, That (after a time to be prefixt) all Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyances, Aſſurances, Laſt Wills, Inſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments and Agreements, concerning Lands, (except Leaſes at Rack) and all Judgments, Statutes, Recognizances, Originals Filed upon Bonds againſt Heirs, and in <hi>Warran' carta, lis pendens in Cancellar',</hi> and all other Acts and Proceſſes, which may in conſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quence affect Lands in Purchaſers Hands,
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:152177:9" rendition="simple:additions"/>ſhall be Regiſtred in <gap reason="blank" extent="1 word">
                  <desc> _____ </desc>
               </gap> days after the Date or Execution, and the Deed or In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrument it ſelf be accordingly Marked, otherwiſe to be Void againſt all ſubſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quent Purchaſers. This is the groſs Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy of the Deſign: <hi>Whence Obſerve,</hi>
               <list>
                  <item>1. That the Deed hath not its Legal Force from the Regiſter, but as for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merly, and as other Inrolled Deeds have; only in Caſe of Loſs, the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſter; (like Inrollments for Safe Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtody) will be a clearer Evidence then any is yet for Repairing them.</item>
                  <item>2. That Men are compelled to Regiſter only their Sales, Mortgages, or Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage Settlements upon Conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion; as for Gifts and voluntary Settlements, they may Injoy their Dear Darling Secreſie.</item>
                  <item>3. That the puzzle and charge to Search in Three, Four, or Five Courts, and in the <hi>Common-Pleas</hi> no leſs than in Three ſeveral Offices, for Judgments, beſides the Rolls Chapel, and with the Clerk of the Peace, for Deeds
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:152177:9"/>Inrolled, at the Fine-Office for Fines and Recoveries, at the Statute-Office for Statutes; and at the Inrollment-Office for Recognizances; with other Places he named, where the Buſineſs of the whole Nation is Collected all together, (all which ſhould be done be every one who would deal upon Judgment and not upon Truſt) is intolerable, and ſometimes pretend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, but ſcarce ever was, ſuppoſing it poſſible, (which he did not grant) to be done compleatly.</item>
                  <item>4. The Buſineſs of Records will be brought into a Searchable compaſs and order, for they will be diſtin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guiſht by Counties, where the Land to be Charg'd lieth, which is in no ſort regarded now, but Judgments moſtly are in ſuch Counties Men pleaſe to chooſe, of which <hi>Middle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſex</hi> and <hi>London</hi> have a ſhare equal with almoſt all <hi>England</hi> beſide.</item>
                  <item>5. Men will not Regiſter all Judgments, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> but only ſuch as they expect
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:152177:10" rendition="simple:additions"/>Uſe of upon Land, which may not be one Fourth part of what are Entred upon the Rolls.</item>
                  <item>6. If Men are Cozen'd by Prior or Double Titles, or Incumbrances, it is their own Fault; <hi>Et ſerra arrecte lour follie.</hi>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </p>
            <p n="3">III. That Incouragement be given, <hi>viz.</hi> That the Firſt Freehold Deed of every Eſtate Regiſtred, ſhall have the Force of a common Recovery and Fine, with Non-Claim, and ſhall not be Void for want of Execution or Formality.</p>
            <p>This will give a quick Growth to the Regiſter, which out of tenderneſs to Men's Scruples, muſt not be compulſive, nor of paſt Acts: For, <hi>Firſt,</hi> Moſt Men that are Awake, will make a Deed of their Eſtates on purpoſe to be Regiſtred; and thence will ariſe a Foundation of Title for moſt Eſtates of <hi>England,</hi> which future times will Build upon.</p>
            <p>And, <hi>Secondly,</hi> This will be a reaſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able and general Purgation of Titles,
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:152177:10"/>ſuch as the Laws intended ſhould be, in particular Caſes, by Fines, the vaſt Bene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit of which to the Nation is obvious.</p>
            <p n="4">IV. That not all the Deed, but only the material part, <hi>viz.</hi> The Date, Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, Conſideration, Limitation, U<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, Conditions, and Powers, be Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſtred; and as for the Parcels, not <hi>Verbatim,</hi> but only the Names of Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors, and Villages, or Town-ſhips: But Recitals, Covenants, and Agreements, that work not on the Legal Eſtate, need not be Regiſtred.</p>
            <p>This would be no long Regiſter, not yet ſo ſhort as the <hi>Scotch</hi> or <hi>Dutch</hi> is; yet ſufficient to ſecure a Purdhaſor. If People affect length in their Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitations and Conditions no harm is done if they pay the more; but he thought it would have contrary ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect, and Men would fall into a way more conciſe, then at preſent is uſed, unleſs it be in Deeds intended to be Inrolled.</p>
            <p n="5">
               <pb n="18" facs="tcp:152177:11" rendition="simple:additions"/>V. That altho' it is not neceſſary to a Regiſter, yet for the convenience of the People dealing in <hi>Longdon,</hi> and the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, there may be Offices in each County, for the Buſineſs of that County; and another in <hi>London,</hi> for the Buſineſs of the whole Nation; And each Man may Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſter in which Office he pleaſe. But then either Office ſhould make Extracts of all that is done, and Weekly tranſmit them to the other; ſo by the Regiſter of the Tranſmiſſions, you may know if any thing be Entred in the other Office.</p>
            <p>As for inſtance; Every <hi>Saturday</hi>'s Poſt ſhould carry the Extracts from <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> and the Return of the ſame Poſt bring up the Extracts from the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try. So that upon the arrival of the Poſt, and the Extract delivered out to the Office, all Parties may ſee, infallibly, if any thing hath been Entred in the other in the former Week, and the Payment of Money may (if they pleaſe) be Suſpended, till ſuch Satisfaction is had. Some
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:152177:11"/>might think this too much Work, and others not exact and full enough: As for the latter, Whoever is ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quainted with the Entries of Fines, which is only <hi>A. B. quer' C. D. deforc' de terris &amp; tenementis in D.</hi> and of what great uſe it is, will not think this method Defective; and for the other, there is not ſo much, but many will skip at the Imployment for moderate Fees.</p>
            <p>You may well imagine how importu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate and teazing we were all upon him, with our Objections and Queries, which made him cry, Hold, ſoft and fair, to take Breath a little, and then give a Reply to what he thought juſtly demanded it: But Firſt, as to the Buſineſs of Objecting in general, he thought,</p>
            <p n="1">I. That the Houſe was too much in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clined to lay weight upon bad Conſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quences objected, which are (perhaps) meer Natural Poſſibilities, and very im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>probable
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:152177:12" rendition="simple:additions"/>probable to fall out, and which in Fact do not ever, or rarely happen in like Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtitutions; and from ſuch remote Poſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bilities, they are made averſe to Regula<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, which carry great and certain Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantages. He thought Men ought to weigh Benefits and Hazards, as Merchants do Profit and Loſs; not caring what the latter is, ſo the other be grater: And alſo conſider, that no human Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtitution ever was, or can be, perfect; but after all the care and contrivance the Wit of Man can apply, to obviate, ſhall or may be abuſed; <hi>Eſce la legge, Eſce la trampa.</hi> If it were now to be propoſed, That any Fact, ſhould by Act of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment be made Capital, might it not be Objected, That then Innocent Perſons might be accuſed, and made to ſuffer Death, by the falſe Teſtimony of one or two Witneſſes? and thoſe perhaps the real Offenders themſelves? And hath not this Abuſe (great as it is) ſometimes hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pened? Yet Capital Laws are neceſſary. This ſhews that no Law can be Eſtabliſht,
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:152177:12"/>but Poſſibilities of Abuſe will lie open upon it: Muſt there be therefore no Law? Such is their Concluſion, who from Poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſibilities of Abuſes, deny their Conſent to a manifeſt good Law. For this Reaſon he diſcharg'd himſelf of all our Clamour on account of Frauds, Forgeries, falſe Entries, and Failings of Officers and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers; for, <hi>ſaid he,</hi> If we ſtartle at ſuch Things, we ought to Reſcind the Juriſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diction of <hi>Kings-Bench, Common-Bench, &amp;c.</hi> whoſe Offices are liable to the ſame, and (if we conſider well) much greater Obje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctions. And yet how often are any ſuch Abuſes there, as falſe Judgments Entred, Men Perſonated or the like? Some have been, 'tis true, but ſo rarely as ſcarce worth mentioning. Men in great Concerns are Naturally Fearful, and when the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cords of an Office are eſteemed Sacred, and Penalties of Abuſing them very high, there is little fear of falſe dealing; if any be, the Nation will not be without Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice to ſet all Right again; and for that End, the fixing ſuch a Power in the chiefs
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:152177:13"/>of our Judges, for ſome time, by the Act, (if any paſs) would not be amiſs.</p>
            <p n="2">II. As to the diſcloſing Men's Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerns, and expoſing their Deeds, whereby their Titles might be called in Queſtion: He ſmiled at the firſt, and ſaid, If he were to Pronounce, Every Man's Debts that Charge his Eſtate, ſhould be wrote in his Forehead; it is only deſign of Fraud, or conſciouſneſs of Folly that makes Men affect Secreſie. And this Humour hath been the Bane of more Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>milies, than Vice and Prodigality: For, Who would not take care to be out of Debts, if all Men's Debts were publick? It is the Secret Shop-Uſury, that Can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kers the Eſtates of <hi>England;</hi> and that will always make open War againſt a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſter. If Debts are known, Men will take Care, either to Diſcharge or Juſtifie them; as by Purchaſing, Matching, or the like; and would not ſneak into Debt as they do, to the ſurprize, and often times Ruin of their Families. O! But if our Debts are known, we loſe advantage
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:152177:13"/>in the Match of our Eldeſt Son, and other Children; I anſwer (ſaid he) that if their Debts are not known, thoſe that Match into their Family are cheated; and which ſhould the Publick take care of, that you ſhould cheat (for it is litte better) or that they, and perhaps your ſelf in your own turn, ſhould not be cheated? in this matter, ſhewing is proving ſufficiently. As to Settlements, if voluntary, they need not be Regiſtred; however he ſaw not the harm of it, if even thoſe were ſo; but why Men ſhould value themſelves as clear Owners of Mortgaged Eſtates, and none able to diſcover the contrary, he was not capable of underſtanding. And he thought a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong the many advantages by a Regiſter, it was not the leaſt, that Men of Eſtates, as in their Converſation, ſo alſo in their Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gotiations, would endeavour to preſerve Honour, and a fair Reputation, and do no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing Senceleſs, and Imprudent; much leſs ſo ruinous to themſelves and Families, as the Trade of ſecret Uſury, at preſent, is.</p>
            <p>As for quarrelling with Titles, he thought
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:152177:14"/>it a Cavil exagerated more for Argument againſt a Regiſter, than otherwiſe; for who now hath a conſiderable Purchaſe Deed made, but by Advice; and the forming a Legal Aſſurance, is not ſuch a Myſtery, but it is practis'd by every Attorney, and ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Clergymen; and ſome Alehouſekeepers make them after Precedents, and in ſmall things not amiſs; perhaps when they are publick, Men will take better care, and go to Councellors as the old way was; which with the Men of his Profeſſion he thought no objection: But here he fell from the Matter, to complain of the Puzzles in Titles from Fines and Recoveries, which he ſaid ſerved for litte in themſelves, but to keep up a Jargon and Miſterious Science, beneficial only to Men of Law and Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers, but a vaſt Charge to the Subject; and that it were well the Law were de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clared more intelligibly; Here one, being charged with another Objection, inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupted him, deſiring he would leave that Matter, and return to the good old Cauſe of a Regiſter; he replied, he was juſt at
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:152177:14"/>it, and ſtraight declared his mind plainly, that were he to rule, he would have e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very Regiſtred Deed have the force of a common Recovery, Fine and Non Claim.</p>
            <p>This let looſe a heavy Charge upon him, for ſeeking to ſupplant ſo many Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers and their Families, who had bought and ſubſiſted by the Buſineſs of Fines and Recoveries, as alſo a Revenue the Crown had from them.</p>
            <p>He ſaid no, he would have the Regiſtry advance, and not diminiſh the Intereſts of all the Officers belonging to the Courts of Juſtice; but it ſhould be in a direct plain way, and not by Ambage and Trick; that is, he would have them made amends, ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther by being made the Officers in the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſtry, (if they thought fit to accept) or elſe by Money at full Rates: and ſo alſo the Intereſt of the Crown might be anſwered And he thought a very ſmall I and Tax, to be collected <hi>gratis,</hi> which all Men would willingly pay, would much more than an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer that Occaſion. He added, that he thought it another infelicity this Affair had
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:152177:15" rendition="simple:additions"/>in Parliament, that, beſides the endeavours of Attorneys, Scriveners, and other Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, who eſteem the Vicious practice of the Law, their gain; there are ſo many Officers of Courts, and in places, who are prudent deſerving Men, and have good E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſteem and Intereſt, but thinking their Free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold, (as they call it) purchaſed with their Money, at ſtake, in the Cauſe, oppoſe a Regiſter with all their force, which hath conſiderable Efficacy; for Men are loath to ſupplant the Livelihood of others not underſerving, without compenſation: there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, whatever Taxes were impoſed on o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Occaſions, he would not have one wanted for this, which he thought no leſs important to the Publick, than any in hand.</p>
            <p>As for the Lawyers, he thought they were in a miſtake, apprehending a Regi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter would curtail their practice; it ſeem'd more probable it would increaſe it; for if Wealth and Security grew from a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giſter, which would ſcarce be denied, Law-Suits would grow no leſs. It was
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:152177:15"/>ever found, that multitude of Dealing produceth Controverſie; and Wealth, Pride and Obſtinacy; Some Counties of <hi>England</hi> formerly noted for Litigiouſneſs, now are very peaceable; not from any late clearneſs grown up in our Laws, but on the contrary, from Great Charges, and incertainty of Succeſs: Beſides, few Law-Suits for Land are now upon nice Queſtions of Conveyancing; but up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Mortagages, Deſcents, Dormant Intails, and the like: The great Land Diſputes now run upon Truſts, and Equities in <hi>Chancery;</hi> in ſo much that the Attorneys at Law are glad to turn Sollicitors there, to be im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed.</p>
            <p>But to conclude (for it grew late) he ſaid, a Regiſter had probably ſucceeded in King <hi>James</hi>'s Parliament, but for one Accident, which was a Jealouſie that the Officers (who muſt be named by the Crown) would be of a Faction not pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per to be general Inſpectors of Mens Eſtates: He thought the Jealouſie not Adequate, but ſo it was; that hint whiſpered, killed
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:152177:16" rendition="simple:additions"/>the Bill. It is not ſo now, ſaid he; but yet I fear Whiſpers, which are often more venemous to good Buſineſſes than open Oppoſition, having been ſo fatal to that at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempt, may alſo be prejudicial to this.</p>
            <p>Upon the whole Matter he would have it confidered, that it is impracticable to frame a Regiſter, without Objection from poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſibility of Abuſe, or perhaps hard Caſes in ſome particulars; which latter may be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>medied (if thought fit) by a power ſet up to relieve for ſome time. Nay, he allowed, that many unforeſeen Abuſes would after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards in practice appear, which no Hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man Wit, or Sagacity could prognoſticate; but he would not have this keep down a good Conſtitution; for, as he ſaid, it was an Objection of the ſame force againſt all Law, and Juriſdictions whatever. And to ſee how little danger there was of that ſort, in this now Diſcourſt of Regiſter; look, ſaid he, to the Fenns, where is a Parliamentary Regiſter eſtabliſh'd, and practic'd for many years; and no Forge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, Abuſe, or ſo much as a Grumble, for
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:152177:16"/>any thing amiſs that he (though a Neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour) ever heard of yet, in the ſurvey of that Office, Let that Example of a very great Benefit in the end, &amp; little or no Abuſe in the practice, anſwer all the Fears and Jealouſies conjured up by Partial Intereſts. Yet, ſaid he, for once grant that many and conſiderable Abuſes may be; are we to be without Parliaments; to regulate and poliſh in time, what perhaps cannot be digeſted in perfection at firſt? Eſtabliſh a Regiſter, lay a Foundation; the Care and Prudence of the beſt Men, will help, by degrees, to give it perfection; and looking forward only, there is no danger of any great harm from it, to any parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cular Perſon whatſoever. And the ſooner this is done, the better; for in proceſs of time it muſt, and therefore will be; Why then ſhould this, or the next Age want it?</p>
            <p>For my own part, I confeſs, theſe Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſes ſo recovered (tho imperfectly) in Writing, have engaged my Opinion moſt clearly, that a Regiſter of Eſtates is not
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:152177:17"/>only uſeful, but almoſt neceſſary to be ſet up in <hi>England,</hi> for the Security of Titles to Land; and conſequently, that it is every Man's Duty to promote it; And it lying not in my way to join in ſo good a Work at preſent, otherwiſe than by making theſe Notes publick; I have committed them to the Stationer, to launch in Print, hoping, (whatever the Nations ſhare is) he may be no loſer, by ſo doing.</p>
            <epigraph>
               <q>
                  <hi>Miſera ſervitus ubi jus eſt vagum.</hi>
               </q>
            </epigraph>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
